Dorothy Thompson Papers
Dorothy Thompson Papers
- Incoming correspondence
  - R - General correspondence
    - Reston, James, 22 Sep 1955; 1 item (Box 24)
    - Ring of Freedom Organizational Materials, 50 items (Box 24)
    - Ring of Freedom, 04 Dec 1931-13 Jan 1942; 68 items (Box 25)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 02 Jun 1941-13 Jun 1941; 2 items (Box 25)
    - Roosevelt, Elanor, 08 Nov 1938-21 Dec 1952; 26 items (Box 25)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 03 Oct 1939-08 Mar 1945; 10 items (Box 25)
    - Rosenstock-Huessey, Eugen, 22 Dec 1944-31 Mar 1957; 32 items (Box 25)
    - Rothchild, Hilda, 18 Apr 1945-12 Dec 1960; 52 items (Box 25)
    - Rubenstein, Marion, 18 Jul 1949-27 Oct 1954; 8 items (Box 25)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 17 Mar 1923; 1 item (Box 25)
    - Ryner, Ernest, 22 Jan 1952-03 Mar 1954; 6 items (Box 25)
  - S - General correspondence
    - Saa-Say, 14 Oct 1930-08 Apr 1960; 58 items (Box 25)
    - Sch-Scu, 17 Oct 1930-13 Sep 1960; 58 items (Box 25)
    - Sdr-She, 18 Nov 1940-29 Jul 1960; 77 items (Box 25)
    - Shi-Sou, 01 May 1935-06 Jan 1961; 686 items (Box 26)
    - Spe-Str, 22 Jun 1931-07 Sep 1960; 102 items (Box 26)
    - Stu-Syr, 12 Dec 1938-01 Feb 1960; 54 items (Box 26)
    - Sachs, Alexander, 07 May 1938-09 Aug 1956; 15 items (Box 26)
    - Salk, Jonas E., 18 Apr 1958; 1 item (Box 26)
    - Sarnoff, David and Lisa, 20 Nov 1944-13 Feb 1959; 13 items (Box 26)
    - Sauk Centre-Sinclair Lewis Main Street Year, 31 May 1960-24 Jul 1960; 1960; 9 items (Box 26)
    - Scheffer, Paul
      - 23 Dec 1938-29 Dec 1946, 51 items (Box 26)
      - 01 Jan 1947-21 Sep 1952, 63 items (Box 26)
      - 25 Jan 1953-29 Dec 1955, 75 items (Box 27)
      - 12 Feb 1956-24 Jan 1959, 33 items (Box 27)
      - Undated, 11 items (Box 27)
    - Schlesinger, Jr., Arthur, 05 Apr 1954; 1 item (Box 27)
    - Schorer, Mark, 28 Apr 1953-13 Sep 1960; 36 items (Box 27)
    - Schwarzenberg, Anna, 14 Jul 1928-11 Jan 1954; 14 items (Box 27)
    - Schwarzwald, Eugenie, 30 Nov 1921-08 Aug 1940; 43 items (Box 27)
    - Sell, Henry Blackman, 31 Mar 1944-25 Dec 1944; 12 items (Box 27)
    - Sergio, Lisa, 18 Jan 1958-13 Apr 1958; 5 items (Box 27)
    - Shaw, Virginia, 31 Mar 1952-19 Jan 1960; 5 items (Box 27)
    - Sheean, Vincent and Dinah
      - 19 Jul 1947-12 Jul 1960, 80 items (Box 27)
      - Undated, 3 folders, 157 items (Box 28)
    - Sherburne, Elizabeth, 11 Jan 1954-05 May 1960; Billings and Sherburne; 18 items (Box 28)
    - Sherwood, Robert E., 19 Aug 1947-26 Aug 1947; 2 items (Box 28)
    - Shirer, William L., 09 Apr 1947-24 Nov 1958; 3 items (Box 28)
    - Simoncic, Klement and Betty, 18 Jan 1949-02 Dec 1960; 14 items (Box 28)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 25 Jan 1928-Mar 1953; 3 items (Box 28)
    - Smathers, George, 19 Aug 1957; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Smith, Harrison, 11 Oct 1949-07 Jul 1952; 7 items (Box 28)
    - Smith, Margaret Chase, 16 Jun 1950-30 Aug 1951; 5 items (Box 28)
    - Sokolosky, George E., 24 Jul 1944-15 Apr 1947; 2 items (Box 28)
    - Sorokin, Pitirima, 23 Apr 1955-03 May 1955; 7 items (Box 28)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E., 05 Aug 1952-22 Sep 1952; 4 items (Box 28)
    - Stimson, Henry L., 21 Oct 1939-14 Apr 1944; 5 items (Box 28)
    - Stout, Rex, 24 Mar 1944-19 Oct 1944; 3 items (Box 28)
    - Strauss, Lewis, 01 Aug 1956; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Studley, Henry, 15 Nov 1939-11 Jan 1947; 41 items (Box 28)
    - Swing, Betty Gram, 26 Apr 1938-25 Jan 1960; 10 items (Box 28)
    - Syracuse University, 23 Nov 1951-17 Jan 1961; 14 items (Box 28)
  - T - General correspondence
    - Taf-Thy, 13 Jul 1934-03 Oct 1960; 53 items (Box 28)
    - Til-Tru, 06 Aug 1923-07 Nov 1958; 56 items (Box 28)
    - Tub-Tyl, 28 Feb 1941-12 Sep 1958; 24 items (Box 28)
    - Theta Sigma Phi, 22 Feb 1954-05 Jul 1954; 9 items (Box 29)
    - This Week Magazine, 02 Mar 1951-31 Dec 1959; 9 items (Box 29)
    - Thomas, Norman, 10 Aug 1947-14 Jan 1957; 6 items (Box 29)
    - Tillich, Paul, 08 Apr 1943-27 Jan 1945; 3 items (Box 29)
    - Time, Inc., 28 Apr 1939-25 Jul 1958; 19 items (Box 29)
    - Tolley, William P., 26 Nov 1951-26 Jan 1961; 9 items (Box 29)
    - Toscanini, Arturo, 22 Jan 1943-25 Dec 1955; 3 items (Box 29)
    - Town Hall, Inc., 12 Mar 1947-29 Sep 1953; 24 items (Box 29)
    - Traeger, Cornelius H., 05 Aug 1940-20 Apr 1959; 11 items (Box 29)
    - Truman, Harry and Bess, 18 Apr 1945-18 May 1950; 4 items (Box 29)
    - Tucci, Niccolo, 06 May 1947-26 Jun 1948; 12 items (Box 29)
  - U - General correspondence
    - U, 01 Jul 1928-19 Jan 1959; 45 items (Box 29)
    - United States Arab-Asian Institute, Inc., 02 Oct 1958-03 Dec 1958; 3 items (Box 29)
    - United States Department of Army, 02 May 1944-04 Feb 1952; 9 items (Box 29)
    - United States Attorney General, 25 Jan 1950; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Office of Censorship, 15 Apr 1942-29 May 1942; 2 items (Box 29)
    - United States Council of the International Chamber of Commerce, 17 Nov 1952; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Department of Defense, 01 Nov 1947-07 Nov 1956; 4 items (Box 29)
    - United States District Court, 10 Feb 1948-29 Jul 1958; 2 items (Box 29)
    - United States Embassy in London, 27 Sep 1955; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Foreign Service, 15 Oct 1941-04 Mar 1957; 22 items (Box 29)
    - United States Information Service, 21 Nov 1950-27 Jun 1956; 5 items (Box 29)
    - United States Department of Interior, 15 Feb 1938-07 Feb 1955; 3 items (Box 29)
    - United States Operations Mission to Iran, 14 Mar 1957; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Department of Justice, 20 Oct 1943-15 Aug 1947; 4 items (Box 29)
    - United States political adviser for Germany, 24 Jun 1945; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Postmaster General, 06 Jan 1944; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States President, 21 Apr 1941-22 May 1953; 10 items (Box 29)
    - United States Public Works Administration, 16 Mar 1936; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Savings and Loan League, 03 Nov 1952-15 Jan 1953; 2 items (Box 29)
    - United States Department of State, 29 Apr 1939-08 Sep 1960; 33 items (Box 29)
    - United States Supreme Court, 23 Oct 1947; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States Treasury Department, 20 Mar 1945-09 Mar 1951; 4 items (Box 29)
    - United States Mission to the United Nations, 28 Jun 1948-10 Sep 1949; 3 items (Box 29)
    - United States Vice President, 14 Dec 1943; 1 item (Box 29)
    - United States War Department, 07 Dec 1942-31 Mar 1947; 10 items (Box 29)
    - United Youth for Victory, 23 Dec 1941-14 Jul 1942; 39 items (Box 30)
    - Urzidil, Johannes, 19 Sep 1949-07 Dec 1960; 37 items (Box 30)
  - V - General correspondence
    - Vag-Ves, 30 Apr 1927-22 Jan 1959; 35 items (Box 30)
    - Vie-Vor, 18 Nov 1930-04 Feb 1958; 61 items (Box 30)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 27 Jul 1945-19 Dec 1950; 12 items (Box 30)
    - Vanguard Press, 03 Jan 1938-11 Jan 1938; 20 items (Box 30)
    - Vierick, Peter, 14 May 1949-05 Aug 1950; undated; 12 items (Box 30)
    - Vischer, Wilhelmina, 12 Jul 1951-26 Jan 1960; 11 items (Box 30)
    - Volunteer Land Corps, 09 Apr 1942-08 Jan 1951; 17 items (Box 30)
    - Volunteer Land Corps organizational material, 19 May 1942-10 Aug 1950; 23 items (Box 30)
    - Von Gebhardt, Hertha, 27 Dec 1946-16 Sep 1947; 12 items (Box 30)
    - Von Hassell, Ulrich, 26 Jul 1945-11 Oct 1947; 5 items (Box 30)
    - Von Moltke, Helmuth and Freya, 23 Jan 1945-30 May 1956; 25 items (Box 30)
    - Von Unruh, Fritz, 18 Apr 1946-09 Mar 1960; 28 items (Box 30)
  - World Organization of Mothers of All Nations
    - 26 Feb 1945-27 Dec 1947, 24 items (Box 31)
    - 14 Jan 1948-31 Dec 1948, 17 items (Box 31)
    - 28 Mar 1949-15 Dec 1949, 38 items (Box 31)
    - 09 Jan 1950-07 Oct 1950, 93 items (Box 31)
    - 14 Feb 1951-21 Dec 1951, 86 items (Box 31)
    - 02 Jan 1952-30 Nov 1952, 51 items (Box 32)
    - 03 Feb 1953-07 Apr 1956, 22 items (Box 32)
    - 07 Nov 1957-11 Sep 1959, 19 items (Box 32)
  - W - General correspondence
    - Wad-War, 23 Jul 1934-10 Sep 1960; 51 items (Box 32)
    - War-Why, 18 Nov 1938-12 Aug 1960; 89 items (Box 32)
    - Wic-Won, 11 Jul 1928-22 Nov 1960; 76 items (Box 32)
    - Woo-Wyl, 28 Apr 1928-11 Dec 1957; 69 items (Box 32)
    - Wallace, Henry Agard, 13 Aug 1942-02 Jan 1945; 7 items (Box 32)
    - Walpole, Hugh, 12 Dec 1923-16 May 1952; 6 items (Box 32)
    - Walton, Leslie Bannister, 19 May 1950-28 Apr 1953; 18 items (Box 32)
    - Wambaugh, Sarah, 29 Apr 1950-15 Jan 1952; 14 items (Box 32)
    - Warren, Dale
      - 20 Mar 1940-28 Nov 1960 (Box 32)
      - Undated (Box 32)
    - Warren, Earl, 01 Mar 1958; 1 item (Box 32)
    - Waterman, Faith, 30 Jan 1948-28 Jun 1960; 169 items (Box 32)
    - Watkins, Ann, Inc., 21 Oct 1941-23 Aug 1946; 20 items (Box 33)
    - Wedding announcements, 29 Oct 1950-18 Apr 1958; 43 items (Box 33)
    - Weisgal, Meyer, 28 Jun 1940-25 Feb 1959; 27 items (Box 33)
    - Wells, Herbert George, 25 Oct 1924-08 Dec 1940; 6 items (Box 33)
    - Wenner-Gren, Axel, 09 Feb 1940-04 Jun 1941; 7 items (Box 33)
    - Wesbrook, Elizabeth, 17 Jan 1952-07 Dec 1958; 8 items (Box 33)
    - West, Rebecca, 09 Dec 1923-06 Dec 1959; 9 items (Box 33)
    - Westbrook, Lasrence, 20 Apr 1942-30 Apr 1958; 6 items (Box 33)
    - Wharton, Edith, 29 Dec 1922-09 Feb 1931; 9 items (Box 33)
    - Wheeler, Burton K., 08 Jul 1944-14 Dec 1946; 4 items (Box 33)
    - White, Paul Dudley, 03 Oct 1958; 1 item (Box 33)
    - Wiatrak, Edward S., 04 Jan 1950-06 Feb 1956; 29 items (Box 33)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 24 Feb 1948; 1 item (Box 33)
    - Willkie, Wendell, 23 Feb 1939-09 Jun 1944; 6 items (Box 33)
    - Winchell, Walter, 04 Feb 1944-15 Apr 1947; 5 items (Box 33)
    - Winsloe, Christa, 04 Nov 1932-09 Dec 1957; 77 items (Box 33)
    - Woollcott, Alexander, 12 Feb 1941-16 Jul 1942; 6 items (Box 33)
    - Wright, Hamilton, 12 Dec 1957-08 May 1958; 15 items (Box 33)
  - Y - General correspondence
    - Y, 06 May 1944-31 May 1956; 26 items (Box 34)
    - Yale University Library, 05 Feb 1951-13 Jan 1958; 11 items (Box 34)
    - Young, Agatha, 18 Sep 1953-07 Jul 1954; 12 items (Box 34)
  - Z - General correspondence
    - Z, 26 Sep 1939-04 Oct 1959; 34 items (Box 34)
    - Zuckmayer, Carl, 19 Dec 1939-15 Jun 1955; 25 items (Box 34)
  - Unidentifiable
    - 10 May 1928-13 Dec 1960, 48 items (Box 34)
- Outgoing correspondence
  - 1918-1934, 27 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: Joseph Bard, Karl Brandt, Theodore Dreiser, Marcel W. Fodor, Sinclair Lewis, Serbia, Suffrage, Triple Entente
    Recipients: Buffalo Evening News, Tish Irwin, Rose Wilder Lane (3), H. L. Mencken, Dale Warren, Helen Woodward
  - 1938, 20 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: "Balance of Power", Herschell Grynszpan, Journalism, Journalist's Defense Fund, Fritz Kortner, Vanguard Press
    Recipients: Paul Scheffer, George Seldes
  - 1939, 27 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: Communism, "Dawn's Early Light", Deportation Case, Germany, Hitler, Propaganda, Eugenie Schwarzwald, Youth
    Recipients: Thomas E. Dewey, Robert Edmondson, James A. Farley, Fritz Kortner, Rose Wilder Lane (2), Joseph Pulitzer, Henry L. Stimson, H. G. Wells
  - Jan-Jun 1940, 16 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: "Another Sun", Biography, "Lindbergism", Franklin D. Roosevelt, Semantics, "Spell Your Name", War
    Recipients: John Chamberlain, Fritz Kortner, Dale Warren, Axel Wenner-Gren
  - Jul-Dec 1940, 20 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: C. C. C. Camps, "Dawn's Early Light", Economics, Fascist Groups, Herschell Grynszpan, Journalist's Defense Fund, Personal Attacks, Russian Alliance, Socialism, Unemployment, Wendell W. Willkie
    Recipients: Lawrence Dennis, Clare Boothe Luce, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Henry L. Stimson, Meyer Weisgal
  - Jan-Apr 1941, 17 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: American Business Interests, Food for France, Germany, Journalist's Defense Fund, Newspapers, Louis Nizer, Norman Thomas, War
    Recipients: Eleanor Roosevelt
  - May-Aug 1941, 32 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: The Federalist, Germany, Herschell Grynszpan, Jewish Questions, Ring of Freedom, War
    Recipients: Karl Mundt, Elmer Rice, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Meyer Weisgal
  - Sep-Dec 1941, 16 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, I.G. Farban Industries, Antonia Valentina Luchaire, Radio Policy, Maria Schneider, "Ten Articles of Personal Faith"
    Recipients: William Paley, Meyer Weisgal
  - Jan 1942, 3 items (Box 35)
    Subjects: Germany, United Youth for Defense, James Warburg
  - Feb 1942, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Broadcasting Problems
    Recipients: Max Ascoli, Alfred Lilienthal
  - Mar 1942, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: German Newspapers
    Recipients: Byron Price
  - Apr 1942, 4 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: United Youth for Defense
    Recipients: Alfred Lilienthal, Charles D. Lockwood
  - May 1942, 5 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: "The Making of Tomorrow"
    Recipients: Alfred Lilienthal
  - Jun 1942, 5 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Definition of "Public Interest", German Newspapers, James Warburg, Child Welfare
    Recipients: Archibald MacLeish
  - Jul 1942, 4 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: The "American Unconscious", Paul Scheffer, Henry Wallace and Herbert Hoover, War
    Recipients: Allen Dulles, John Moses, Raoul de Roussy de Sales
  - Aug 1942, 3 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Paul Scheffer, Volunteer Land Corps
  - Sep 1942, 1 item (Box 36)
    Subjects: Volunteer Land Corps
  - Oct 1942, 4 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Government and the Press, India, War's Effects
    Recipients: Robert Littell, Franklin D. Roosevelt
  - Nov 1942, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: "European Federation"
    Recipients: Jacques Maritain
  - Dec 1942, 4 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: "Listen Hans"
    Recipients: John Moses
  - 1942, undated, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Communism
    Recipients: Sumner Welles
  - Jan-Feb 1943, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: British-United States Relations, Europe
  - Mar 1943, 1 item (Box 36, Box 35)
  - Apr 1943, 7 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Herman Budzislawski, Motion Pictures, Post-War Germany
    Recipients: Howard Deitz, Paul Tillich
  - May 1943, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Sinclair Lewis, Motion Pictures
    Recipients: Bennett Cerf, Quincy Howe
  - Sep 1943, 1 item (Box 36)
    Subjects: War Food
    Recipients: Marvin Jones
  - Oct 1943, 3 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: The Classics, The English Language, Europe, Japanese Propaganda
    Recipients: Burgess Johnson
  - Nov 1943, 3 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Maxim Kopf, Thanksgiving Wishes
  - Dec 1943, 8 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Censorship, "Czecho-Slovakia", German People
    Recipients: E. J. King
  - Jan 1944, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Censorship, Germany, The Ideal President, Movies
    Recipients: Bruce Bliven, Byron Price, Spyros Skouras
  - Feb 1944, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Family Economics, Maxim Kopf, "View"
    Recipients: William F. Cronin, Thomas E. Dewey
  - Mar 1944, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Freedom House
    Recipients: Gertrude Lawrence
  - Apr 1944, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Economic Centralization, Freedom House, Italian Exiles, "Pan-Germany"
    Recipients: Thomas E. Dewey, Beatrice Gould, Cordell Hull, Loren Price, Rex Stout
  - May 1944, 6 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Political Campaigns, The Press
    Recipients: Franklin D. Roosevelt
  - Jun 1944, 4 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: India, Informants, Writers
    Recipients: Writers' War Board
  - Jul 1944, 1 item (Box 36)
  - Aug 1944, 7 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Committee for a Democratic Germany, Force for Peace, Nazi Party, Volunteer Land Corps, Women's Action Committee for Victory and Lasting Peace
    Recipients: John Bainbridge, Allen W. Gullion
  - Oct 1944, 2 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Propaganda Aims
  - Nov 1944, 4 items (Box 36)
    Recipients: James Mead
  - Dec 1944, 1 item (Box 36)
  - 1945, 11 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: American League for the United States of Europe, Europe, Yalta Conference
    Recipients: Berton K. Wheeler, Franklin D. Roosevelt
  - 1946, 25 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Autobiographical, Conscience, Hans Deichmann, Germany, Hitlerism, Price Controls, Russia, Writers' War Board
    Recipients: The Daily Worker, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Baron von Rheinbaben, Vincent Sheean, Rex Stout
  - Jan-Jun 1947, 31 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Bill of Rights, Hermann Borchardt, Coal Miners, Communist Party, Europe, Foreign Language Press, Germany, Harvard Salzburg Seminar, Maxim Kopf, The Polish People, Taxation, United Nations
    Recipients: Karl Brandt, Victor Grosz, John Gunther, J. Edgar Hoover, John L. Lewis, Robert Patterson, Frances Perkins, George Sokolosky, Robert Taft, Arthur Vandenburg, Meyer Weisgal
  - Jul-Dec 1947, 32 items (Box 36)
    Subjects: Marcel W. Fodor, "The Idea of Europe", Italian Treaty, Niccolo Tucci, United Stations Real Estate, Development, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Lucius Clay, Felix Frankfurter, Hasting Lionel Ismay, John C. Knox, Robert Lovett, Jan Masaryk, The New York Times, Vincent Sheean, Arthur Watkins
  - Jan-Aug 1948, 61 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Robert Best, Communism, Czechoslovakia, "The European Digest", European Confederation, Farm Management, Lewis L. Incze, India, Italy, Jan Masaryk, Negro Question, Palestine Partition, Ferdinand Peroutka, Personal Attacks, Prisoners of War Camps, Russia, Richard Tauber, United States Foreign Policy, Voice of America, W.O.M.A.N., World Situation
    Recipients: Joseph Alsop, Charles Bartlett, Ernest Bevin, William Beveridge, Lucius Clay, Elmer Davis, Charles de Gaulle, Ralph Flanders, James Forrestal, Virginia Gildersleeve, H. L. L'Heureux, Walter Lippmann, Robert Lovett, George Marshall, Eleanor Roosevelt, Carlo Sforza, Vincent Sheean, M. J. Slavic, Harry S. Truman, Thornton Wilder
  - Oct-Dec 1948, 18 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Germany, Ferdinand Peroutka, U.N.E.S.C.O., W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Walter Lippmann, Stella Reading, Carlo Sforza
  - Mar-Jan 1949, 30 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Herman Budzislawski, F. F. Coady, Hans Deichmann, René Fueloep-Miller, Jewish Atrocities, Personal Attack, Dimitri Shostokovitch, Helmuth von Moltke, Zionism
    Recipients: Dean Acheson, Elmer Berger, Erich Fischer, Benjamin Hibbs, Professional, Benjamin Rosenthal, Vincent Sheean, Arthur Vandenburg
  - Jun-Aug 1949, 34 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Immigration, Maxim Kopf, Strike-Bell Syndicate vs. Newspaper Guild
    Recipients: Max Eastman, George Marshall, Grace Sims Peat, Petra Vermehren
  - Sep-Dec 1949, 62 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Communist Party, Stubens Pond Club, Zionism
    Recipients: Henry Andrews, Elmer Berger, Cleveland Plain Dealer, Richard Coudenhove-Kalgeri, James Drawbell, Daniel Frisch, Peta Fuller, Virginia Gildersleeve, John Haynes Holmes, Hildegard Kiep, William Loeb, H. L. Mencken, Dinah Sheean, Harrison Smith, Countess von Goertz, Dale Warren, Lawrence Westbrook
  - Jan 1950, 33 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Jewish Hostages, The Saar, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Bell Syndicate, Elmer Berger, Miles Bouton, Cleveland Plain Dealer, Thomas Connally, Patrick Dudensing, Normal Littell, Henrik Mannerfrid, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Ala Story, Petra Vermehren
  - Feb 1950, 35 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Bureau of Fine Arts, Korea, Russia, Rebecca West, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Bell Syndicate, William Rose Benet, Peter Drucker, Bruce and Beatrice Gould, William Loeb, Helen Martin, John Morse, Paul Scheffer
  - Mar 1950, 43 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Edward Bellamy, Lucius Clay, Francisco Franco, Germany, Palestine, Lawrence Westbrook, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Thomas Connally, Herbert Hoover, Reinhold Niebuhr, Vincent Sheean, Petra Vermehren, John Wheeler
  - Apr 1950, 27 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Catholicism, Lucius Clay, Far Eastern Policy, Ernest Hemingway, Syracuse University, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Bernard Baruch, Thomas Connally, Ralph Flanders, Bruce and Beatrice Gould, Victor Lasky, Norman Littell, Sanford Ross, David Sarnoff, Vincent Sheean, Harrison Smith
  - May 1950, 31 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Richard Buhlig, Germany, Katyn Massacre Committee, The Kinsey Report, Morganthau Plan, Vincent Sheean, Harry S. Truman
    Recipients: Karl Deichmann, Bruce Gould, Alfred Lilienthal, William Loeb
  - Jun 1950, 27 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Aggression vs. Resistance, American Friends of the Middle East, Bavarian Refugee Administration, Committee for the Prevention of World War III, "Hold Berlin" Rally, Korea, Personal Attacks, W.O.M.A.N., Women in Politics
    Recipients: Peter Drucker, Thomas Finletter, Frederika, Queen of Greece, Norman Littell, Margaret Chase Smith
  - Jul 1950, 16 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Atomic Energy, Common Cause, Incorporated
    Recipients: René Fueloep-Miller, Roy de Grout, Arthur Bliss Lane
  - Aug 1950, 24 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Germany, Governorship of California, Effie Purcell, United Nations, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Richard E. Byrd, Bruce and Beatrice Gould, Walter Lippmann, Grace Sims Peat, Cornelius Traeger, Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr
  - Sep 1950, 10 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Middle East, Harry S. Truman
    Recipients: Lynn Atkinson
  - Oct 1950, 26 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Autobiographical, Yusif el Banak, Germany, Middle East, Tibet, W.O.M.A.N., Zionism
    Recipients: Alfred Lilienthal, Jack Wheeler
  - Nov 1950, 11 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: René Fueloep-Miller
    Recipients: Henry Andrews, William A. Eddy, Margaret Kirwin, Caroline Newton
  - Dec 1950, 11 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Middle East, Zionists
    Recipients: Marcel W. Fodor, Benjamin Hibbs, Pamela Wilson
  - Jan 1951, 13 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Peter Bon de Sousa Pernes
    Recipients: Marcel W. Fodor, Walter Lippmann, Porter Sargent, Dale Warren
  - Feb 1951, 18 items (Box 37)
    Subjects: Communism, Containment, Maxim Kopf, Korea, Harry S. Truman, Fritz von Unruh
    Recipients: Robert Taft, Jack Wheeler
  - Mar 1951, 39 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Biography, Germany, Alexander Hamilton, Maxim Kopf, Sinclair Lewis, Middle East, Peace Plans, Russia, Vincent Sheean, Johannes Urzidil
    Recipients: Shannon Allen, Ralph Bell, Bell Syndicate, Bruce Gould, Norman Littell, Martha Morse, Grace Sims Peat, Herbert Pell, Edward Weeks, John Wheeler, William Zuckerman
  - Apr 1951, 29 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Anti-semitism, Fouad Farouk, Foundations, The Free Press, Middle East, Edna St. Vincent Millay, Margaret Wilson
    Recipients: Shannon Allen, Kenneth Bannister, Cosmopolitan Club, Peter Drucker, Ralph Flanders, C. S. Freeman, Paul Scheffer, William Zuckerman
  - May 1951, 30 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Jewish Question, MacArthur-Truman Debate, Middle East
    Recipients: Henry Andrews, C.A.R.E., Ralph Flanders, Tish Irwin, Jacques Maritain, John Flourney Montgomery, Grace Sims Peat, Dinah Sheean, Vincent Sheean, Theodore Weeks, Jack Wheeler
  - Jun 1951, 17 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Reine de Sales, Jan Masaryk, Zionism
    Recipients: Elmer Davis, Peter Drucker, Ralph Flanders, Virginia Gildersleeve, William Ernest Hocking, Walter Lippmann, Jean Marie Richard
  - Jul 1951, 26 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Feminism, Israel, Korea, Sinclair Lewis, O'Dwyer, Russia, Vincent Sheean, Harry S. Truman
    Recipients: James Babb, C.A.R.E., Bruce and Beatrice Gould, Paul Scheffer, Whitney Shepardson, Arthur Sulzberger, Johannes Urizidil
  - Aug 1951, 15 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Middle East, W.O.M.A.N., Zionism
    Recipients: Ralph Bell, Virginia Gildersleeve, Ernest Hocking, Mary Hughes, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Harold Peat
  - Sep 1951, 26 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Anglo-Iranian Oil, Asia, C.A.R.E., Middle East, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Henry Andrews, Ralph Bell, Pearl S. Buck, Millar Burrows, Cornelius Van Engert, C. S. Freeman, Margaret Chase Smith
  - Oct 1951, 11 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Sinclair Lewis, Vincent Sheean